Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm Microfilm Investigations, 1913-1950 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm Microfilm Investigations 1913-1950 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company.
3.0 Linear Feet 53 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States.
The JWT 16mm Microfilm Investigations span the years 1913-1950 and consist of research reports, market studies, account histories, office overviews, campaign studies and other investigative documents. Clients include Andrew Jergens, Ballantine, Corning, Kodak, Emerson Drug, General Cigar, J&J Colman, J.B. Williams, J.P. Stevens, Johns-Manville, Lehn & Fink, Lever Brothers (Unilever), Lorillard, Northam Warren, Penick & Ford, Pond's, R.T. French, Scott Paper, Standard Brands and the U.S. Marine Corps. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm Microfilm Investigations were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Historical Note
Beginning in the 1930s, documents from several JWT departments and functions were microfilmed, including Legal Department, Treasurer's Office, As Broadcast Scripts and Commercials for Radio and Television, Investigations, Publicity Department, Artwork, Consumer Panel, and Radio/Television Department. Documents were microfilmed in no order, and typed and hand-written indices were produced for the microfilms. It is believed that once microfilmed, most of the original documents were destroyed.
Collection Overview
The JWT 16mm Microfilm Investigations span the years 1913-1950 and consist of research reports, market studies, account histories, office overviews, campaign studies and other investigative documents. Clients include Andrew Jergens, Ballantine, Corning, Eastman Kodak, Emerson Drug, General Cigar, J&J Colman, J.B. Williams, J.P. Stevens, Johns-Manville, Lehn & Fink, Lever Brothers (Unilever), Lorillard, Northam Warren, Penick & Ford, Pond's, R.T. French, Scott Paper, Standard Brands and the U.S. Marine Corps.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged by reel number and by the order of documents therein. Documents were microfilmed in no order. An alphabetical listing of companies and organizations is provided, followed by a more detailed contents listing of the reels. The present finding aid only documents microfilmed items identified under the category of Investigations.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
J. Walter Thompson Company
Andrew Jergens Company (Cincinnati, Ohio)
Chesebrough-Pond's.
Corning Glass Works
Eastman Kodak Company
Emerson Drug Company
General Cigar Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
J.B. Williams Co
Johns-Manville Corporation
Lehn & Fink
Northam Warren Corporation
P. Ballantine & Sons
P. Lorillard Company
Penick & Ford, Ltd
R.T. French Company
Scott Paper Company
Standard Brands Incorporated
Stevens (J.P.) Company, Roanoke Rapids, N.C.
Unilever (Firm)
United States. Marine Corps
Advertising
Advertising -- United States
Advertising -- United States -- History
Advertising agencies
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Advertising research
Marketing research
Microfilms
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising Vertical Files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Media Resources and Research Department Records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Non-Proprietary Research Reports
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Research Department Records
McGraw-Hill Marketing Information Center Vertical File
Detailed Description of Collection
- Index to Investigations
  - A. Guinness & Son & Co., Ltd., 1937-1939, Reel 221-222
  - A.C. Krumm & Sons: macaroni, 1926, Reel 46
  - A.M. Karagheusian, Inc.: rugs, 1926, Reel 196
  - Absorbine Jr., 1937-1938, Reel 711
  - American Writing Paper Co., 1919, Reel 195
  - Andrew Jergens Co.
    - 1922-1936, Reel 45-46
    - 1929-1934, Reel 196
    - 1930-1931, Reel 222
  - Aqua-Velva: See J.B. Williams Co.
  - Arbuckle Brothers: Yuban Coffee, 1913-1923, Reel 195
  - Artloom Rugs, 1936, Reel 195
  - Associated Tile Manufacturing Co., 1928-1931, Reel 195
  - Atlantic Coast Fisheries, 1929, Reel 195
  - Aunt Jemima Pancake Flour, 1924-1928, Reel 47
  - Automobile trunks and baggage carriers: See Kari-Keen Mfg.
  - Autostrap Safety Razor Co., 1918-1922, Reel 195
  - B.F. Goodrich Co., 1928-1932, Reel 39, 45, 196
  - Bakers of America, 1918, Reel 195
  - Baldwin Laboratories: Dwin insecticide, 1940, Reel 220-221
  - Baldwin Piano Co., 1930, Reel 195
  - Ballantine Ale & Beer
    - 1935-1936, Reel 37
    - 1937-1941, Reel 711
  - Block Drug Co., 1942-1944, Reel 256
  - Blue Cross: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Bovril: See Lehn & Fink
  - Branch Office Reports: See J. Walter Thompson Co.
  - Brer Rabbit Molasses: See Penick & Ford
  - Bromo-Seltzer: See Emerson Drug Co.
  - Burry Biscuit Co.
    - 1936-1937, Reel 37
    - 1947-1949, Reel 195
  - Buston, Inc., 1924-1930, Reel 47
  - Butterick Publishing Co., 1904-1925, Reel 195
  - Calsodent, 1930, Reel 38
  - Carter Ink Co., 1930, Reel 49
  - Carter Products, 1942-1944, Reel 337
  - Ceco Manufacturing Co.: radio tubes, 1930, Reel 195
  - Certo: See Douglas Pectin Co.
  - Chain stores, 1925, Reel 38
  - Chase & Sanborn: See Standard Brands
  - Chatham Blankets, 1929-1931, Reel 38
  - Chesebrough-Pond's, 1936-1938, Reel 38
  - Cigarettes: See P. Lorillard Co.; New business; Union tobacco Co.
  - City Baking Co.
    - 1924-1927, Reel 49
    - 1934-1936, Reel 38
    - 1939-1940, Reel 220
  - Coca-Cola: See New Business
  - Coconuts: See Franklin Baker Co.
  - Coffee: See Arbuckle Bros.; Maxwell House; Standard Brands
  - Connecticut, Hartford: See National defense; Newspapers
  - Consumer Panel Department
    - Cigarettes, 1944-1946, Reel 384
    - Clothing, 1943-1945, Reel 380-383, 389-91
    - Cosmetics, 1940-1945, Reel 389
    - Liniments, 1941-1945, Reel 391
    - Soaps, 1940-1946, Reel 384, 387-88
    - Standard Brancds -- coffee, 1947-1948, Reel 373-74
  - Corning Glass Works
    - 1925-1928, Reel 195
    - 1925-1939, Reel 38
  - Corona, 1930, Reel 49
  - Corsets: See Kups Bros.
  - Curtis Flying Service, 1929, Reel 38
  - Curtis Publishing Co., 1933-1937, Reel 38
  - Cutex: See Northam Warren
  - Danderine, 1933, Reel 39
  - Dentifrices: See Foreign investigations (Argentina, Mexico, Cuba)
  - Douglas Pectin Co.: Certo, 1925-1929, Reel 195
  - Drug stores, 1931, Reel 60
  - Durham-Duplex Razor Co.: Enders Razors
    - 1932-1938, Reel 221
    - 1934-1938, Reel 195
  - Dwight Manufacturing Co.: Dwight Anchor Sheeting, 1925-1926, Reel 195-196
  - Dwin insecticide: See Baldwin Laboratories
  - Eastman Kodak
    - 1930, Reel 198
    - 1930-1933, Reel 39
    - 1933-1935, 1938-1940, Reel 444
  - Easy Washing Machine Co.
    - 1938, Reel 196, 198
    - 1938-1939, Reel 338
  - Ed Pinaud, 1925, Reel 197
  - Emerson Drug Co.
    - 1935-1940, Reel 37
    - 1938-1940, Reel 220
    - Bromo-Seltzer, 1935, Reel 196
  - Enders Razors: See Durham-Duplex Razor Co.
  - Fanny Farmer: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Financial advertising, 1930-1935, Reel 39
  - Fleischmann Gin
    - 1935-1937, Reel 57
    - 1936-1937, Reel 196
  - Fleischmann's yeast: See Standard Brands
  - Florida Citrus Industry, 1935-1941, Reel 427
  - Foreign Investigations See also J. Walter Thompson Co.: Branch Office Reports:
    - Argentina
      - 1929-1935, Reel 257
      - 1936, Reel 232
      - Dentifrices, 1947, Reel 713
      - General Motors & others, 1929-1932, 1935, Reel 222
    - Australia
      - 1918, 1930-1935, Reel 222
      - 1929-1937, Reel 223
      - Horlick's, 1938-1939, Reel 232
      - Kellogg's, 1938, Reel 232
      - Kellogg's, 1942, Reel 427
      - Sydney, 1929-1935, Reel 257
    - Belgium
      - 1927, Reel 257
      - 1927, 1929, Reel 223
      - General Motors, 1937, Reel 257
    - Brazil
      - 1931, 1934, Reel 223
      - Sao Paulo, 1929-1935, Reel 257
    - Canada
      - 1930-1933, Reel 223
      - 1931-1934, 1938, Reel 224
      - Kellogg's, 1938, Reel 232
      - Lever Brothers, 1938, Reel 233
      - Lever Brothers, soups, 1940-1944, Reel 338
      - Montreal, 1929-1935, Reel 257
      - Toronto, 14930-1935, Reel 257
    - Cuba
      - Dentifrices, 1947, Reel 713
      - Standard Brands, 1945, Reel 713
    - Denmark
      - 1921-1931, Reel 224
      - 1927-1935, Reel 257
    - Egypt, 1928-1930, Reel 224
    - Finland, 1927, Reel 224
    - France
      - 1927-1935, Reel 257
      - 1927-1937, Reel 224
    - Germany
      - 1927-1930, Reel 224
      - 1928-1930, Reel 232
      - Berlin, 1933, Reel 257
    - Great Britain
      - 1899-1935, Reel 257
      - 1922-1934, 1937, Reel 225
      - 1925-1929, Reel 224
      - 1925-1939, Reel 232
      - Kellegg's, 1937-1939, Reel 232
    - Holland
      - 1927, Reel 225
      - The Hague, 1927-1935, Reel 257
    - India
      - 1929, 1931, Reel 225
      - 1938-1939, Reel 232
      - India Bombay, 1929-1935, Reel 257
    - International advertising 149-page summary of JWT as an international agency,w ith short reports on individual offices, as listed below; some include research data, 1935, Reel 257
    - Japan, 1932, Reel 225
    - Mexico (dentifrices), 1947, Reel 713
    - New Zealand, 1931, Reel 225
    - Norway, 1927, 1931, Reel 225
    - Poland, 1927, Reel 225
    - Puerto Rico (Standard Brands), 1945, Reel 713
    - Romania--Bucharest, 1930-1935, Reel 257
    - South Africa
      - 1929-1931, Reel 225
      - Cape Town, 1928-1935, Reel 257
    - South America report of Pan Am-sponsored goodwill tour, 1941, Reel 257
    - Spain, 1927-1931, Reel 225
    - Sweden
      - 1927-1930, Reel 225
      - 1929-1932, Reel 232
    - Switzerland, 1927, Reel 232
    - Uruguay, 1930, Reel 232
  - Foremost Dairy Products, Inc., 1929-1930, Reel 39
  - Franklin Baker Co.: coconuts, 1922-1929, Reel 195
  - General Cigar Co.
    - 1932-1936, Reel 39
    - 1937-1940, Reel 711
  - General Electric Co., after 1939, Reel 444
  - General Information (approx. misc. reports), 1935-1944, Reel 338
  - General Motors: See Foreign Investigations
  - Golden Bear Cookies, 1930, Reel 196
  - Good Housekeeping, 1940, Reel 221
  - Goodyear, 1936-1938, Reel 45
  - Gorham Co.
    - 1929-1930, Reel 106
    - 1936, Reel 45
  - Grove's Bromo-Quinine, 1941, Reel 221
  - H.P. Hood & Sons, Inc: milk, 1933, Reel 106
  - Hathaway Bakeries, 1928-1931, Reel 45
  - Herbert Taryton Cigarettes: See Union Tobacco Co.
  - Horlick's: See Foreign Investigations (Australia); Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Insurance (See also Life Insurance), 1934, Reel 45
  - International Printing Ink, 1930, Reel 196
  - International Shoe Co., 1925, Reel 198
  - Irving Trust Co.: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - J & J Colman, Ltd.
    - 1924-1930, Reel 38
    - 1933-1936, 1938-1940, Reel 256
    - 1935, Reel 196
  - J. Walter Thompson Co.: Branch office Reports, including Chicago, London, Montreal, San Francisco, Seattle, Wall St., 1937-1939, 1942, Reel 256
  - J.B. Williams (Shaving & toilet products)
    - 1936-1937, Reel 256
    - 1933-1936, Reel 60
    - 1937-1939, Reel 415
    - 1941-1942, Reel 427
    - Audit Bureau sales reports, 1941, Reel 221
  - J.C. Penney Co.
    - 1928, Reel 197
    - 1937, Reel 52
  - J.P. Stevens Co.: Peace Dale Yarns
    - 1920-1926, Reel 197
    - 1923-1924, Reel 52
    - 1926, Reel 198
  - Jell-O: See New Business
  - Johns-Manville, Inc.
    - 1927-1933, Reel 46
    - 1933-1935, Reel 221
    - 1936-1941, Reel 444
    - 1949, Reel 713
  - Johnson & Johnson (160 pages total), 1924-1926, Reel 106
  - Kari-Keen Manufacturing Co.: auto trucks & baggage carriers, 1929, Reel 196
  - Kellogg Co. (See also Foreign Investigations: Australia, Canada, Great Britain), 1938-1939, Reel 233
  - Kent-Coslikyan: rugs, 1921, Reel 196
  - Kraft Cheese: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Kraft-Phenix Cheese Co., 1924-1935, Reel 46
  - Kups Bros.: Nemo corsets, 1924-1934, Reel 46
  - La Gerardine, 1929-1930, Reel 46
  - Lamont, Corliss & Co.: See Pond's Extract Co.
  - Laundry problems, 1921-1925, Reel 46
  - Lehn & Fink
    - Bovril, 1927, Reel 195
    - Bovril, 1928, Reel 196
    - Pebeco Tooth Paste, 1923, 1926, Reel 197
  - Lever Brothers (For Canada see Foreign Investigations)
    - 1921-1937, Reel 46-47
    - 1925-1937, Reel 251
    - 1929-1932, Reel 233
    - 1934, 1936, Reel 256
    - Gallup reports, 1933, Reel 251
    - Gallup reports, 1933-1939, Reel 250
    - Lifebuoy, 1919, Reel 197
    - Lux Flakes, 1932-1934, 1936-1937, Reel 256
    - Lux Flakes, 1937-1938, Reel 711
    - Lux Radio Theatre, 1935-1940, Reel 2250-251
    - Lux Radio Theatre, 1938-1939, Reel 712
    - Lux Radio Theatre: Jury Reports on Plays, 1939, Reel 233
    - Lux Toilet Soap, 1939-1941, Reel 712
    - Rinso, 1919-1925, Reel 197
    - Vimms, 1944-1945, Reel 338
  - Libby, McNeill & Libby, 1923-1930, Reel 47
  - Libby's: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Life insurance (See also Insurance)
    - 1938-1939, Reel 712-713
    - 1939-1944, 1948, Reel 444
  - Lipstick: See Northam Warren
  - Lysol, 1925, Reel 47
  - Macaroni: See A.C. Krumm & Sons
  - Market studies, 1940-1941, 1943-1945, Reel 378
  - Martex, 1929, Reel 197
  - Martini & Rossi: vermouth, 1939-1941, Reel 221
  - Maxwell House Coffee, 1927-1929, Reel 47
  - Mayonnaise: See Richard Hellman, Inc.
  - Media analysis, 1932-1934, Reel 47
  - Milk: See H.P. Hood & Sons
  - Miscellaneous accounts (incl. Planters, Reader's Digest, Fanny Farmer, Reynolds, Libby's, Irving Trust, Blue Cross, Kraft Cheese, Horlick's, Warner Bros., New York subways), 1943-1945, Reel 378
  - Mouthwash: See New Business
  - National Biscuit Co., 1923-1935, Reel 49
  - National Defense: survey of attitudes, Hartford, Conn., 1941, Reel 256
  - National Lumber Association, 1928, Reel 49, 197
  - Navy Air, 1942-1943, Reel 338
  - Nemo Corsets: See Kups Bros.
  - New Business
  - Coca-Cola, Woolworth's, Jell-O, cigarettes (many more, listed on reels), 1923-1936, Reel 49, 51-52
  - Woolworth's cigarettes, mouthwash, razor blades, 1937-1941, Reel 256-57
  - U.S. Marine Corps, oranges, 1941, Reel 712
  - New York subways: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - New York Times, 1927, Reel 59
  - New York University market survey, 1936, Reel 52
  - Newspaper circulation study, 1929, Reel 49
  - Newspapers: survey of attitudes, Hartford Conn., 1941, Reel 256
  - Northam Warren
    - 1928-1937, Reel 59-60
    - Cutex, 1916-1928, Reel 38-39
    - Cutex, 1937-1940, Reel 257
    - Cutex, 1940-1946, Reel 337-338
    - Cutex and Odorono, 1934-1945, Reel 197
    - lipstick, 1928-1935, Reel 196
    - Odorono, 1926-1929, Reel 53
    - Odorono, 1934, Reel 52
    - Odorono, 1935-1937, Reel 221
  - Old Gold cigarettes: See P. Lorillard Co.
  - Oranges: See New business
  - Owens-Illinois Glass Co., 1943-1944, Reel 712
  - P. Lorillard Co. (Old Gold cigarrettes)
    - 1941-1944, Reel 376
    - 1940-1941, Reel 256
  - Panama Pacific, 1935, Reel 52
  - Peace Dale Knitting Yarn: See J.P. Stevens Co.
  - Pebeco Tooth Paste: See Lehn & Fink
  - Penick & Ford
    - 1921-1931, Reel 52
    - Brer Rabbit Molasses, 1932-1933, Reel 196-97
    - Brer Rabbit Molasses, 1933-1937, Reel 712
  - Pennsylvania Railroad
    - 1926-1932, Reel 52
    - 1931-1932, Reel 197
  - Pertussin: See Seecke & Kade
  - Peter's Chocolate
    - 1922, 1926, Reel 196
    - 1924-1932, Reel 52
  - Account history, 1919, Reel 427
  - Phoenix Hosiery, 1931, Reel 49
  - Pineapple Producers Co-operative Assn., Ltd., 1933-1935, Reel 197
  - Planter's: See Standard Brands; Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Pond's Extract Co. (Lamont, Corliss & Co.)
    - 1924-1930, Reel 52-53
    - 1934-1936, Reel 221
    - 1936-1938, Reel 233
    - 1936-1941, Reel 256
    - 1938-1941, Reel 712
  - Postal Telegraph, 1929, Reel 197
  - President Suspender Co., 1924, Reel 197
  - Publication surveys, 1931, Reel 59
  - R.T. French Co.
    - 1929-1934, Reel 39
    - 1933-1936, Reel 256
    - 1936-1939, Reel 338
    - 1937, Reel 196
    - 1939-1941, Reel 711
  - Radio tubes: See Ceco Manufacturing Co.
  - Razor blades: See New Business
  - Reader's Digest: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Reckitts (overseas) Ltd., 1937, Reel 196
  - Retail trading, 1928, Reel 53
  - Reynolds: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Richard Hellman, Inc.: mayonnaise, 1926-1927, Reel 196
  - Rinso: See Lever Brothers
  - Royal Baking Powder
    - 1923-1931, Reel 57
    - 1923-1937, Reel 197
    - 1932-1934, Reel 58
  - Royal Gelatin & Pudding, 1933-1940, Reel 58
  - Royal Mayonnaise, 1930, Reel 54
  - Rugs: See A.M. Karagheusian; Kent-Coslikyan
  - Rural and small town
    - 1923, 1925, Reel 54
    - 1924, Reel 53, 60
  - S.W. Straus, 1928-1930, Reel 59
  - Sauerkraut, 1937, Reel 196
  - Scott Paper Co.
    - 1926-1930, Reel 53-54
    - 1932-1933, 1935-1938, Reel 257
    - 1939-1942, Reel 713
  - Seecke & Kade (Pertussin)
    - 1931, Reel 196
    - 1933-1941, Reel 221
  - Sharpe & Dohme
    - 1929-1936, Reel 54
    - 1932, Reel 257
    - 1944-1945, Reel 444
  - Shaving products: See J.B. Williams Co.
  - Shell Oil Co.
    - 1932-1936, Reel 53
    - 1937-1939, Reel 378
  - Simmons Co.
    - 1926-1929, Reel 53
    - 1927-1932, Reel 54
    - 1932, 1938, Reel 197
  - Skol Co., Inc., 1937-1940, Reel 233
  - Smokader manufacturing Co., 1924-1928, Reel 197
  - Special Studies
    - 1923-1933, Reel 54
    - 1935, Reel 57
  - St. Denis Bath Salts, 1929, Reel 197
  - Standard Brands, Inc. (See also Consumer Panel Department; Foreign investigations: Cuba, Puerto Rico)
    - 1930-1935, Reel 58
    - 1933-1935, Reel 57
    - 1935-1937, Reel 221
    - 1937-1939, 1945, Reel 377
    - 1940-1942, Reel 713
    - Chase & Sanborn, 1929-1934, Reel 56
    - Chase & Sanborn, 1931-1934, Reel 49
    - Chase & Sanborn, 1935-1936, Reel 57
    - Chase & Sanborn, 1936-1939, Reel 233
    - Chase & Sanborn, 1939-1940, Reel 377-378
    - Chase & Sanborn, 1941, Reel 444
    - Chase & Sanborn, 1942-1943, 1945-1946, Reel 711
    - Chase & Sanborn pamphlets, 1948-1949, Reel 427
    - Fleischmann's Yeast, 1922-1934, Reel 54-55
    - Fleischmann's Yeast, 1926-1927, Reel 196
    - Fleischmann's yeast, 1930-1934, Reel 49
    - Fleischmann's Yeast, 1934-1948, Reel 56
    - Fleischmann's Yeast, 1936-1939, Reel 59
    - Fleischmann's Yeast, 1937-1938, Reel 233
    - Fleischmann's Yeast, 1938-1939, Reel 256
    - Fleischmann's Yeast, 1939-1941, Reel 444
    - Fleischmann's Yeast contest, 1927, Reel 56
    - Mr. Bailey's files, 1923, 1931-1938, Reel 427
    - Planter's Peanuts (See also Miscellaneous Accounts), 1933-1942, Reel 221
    - Tender Leaf Tea, 1934-1940, Reel 233
    - Tender Leaf Tea, 1940-1942, 1946-1949, Reel 376-77
  - Stephen F. Whitman & Son, Inc.: chocolate, 1926, Reel 198, 220
  - Sterno Corp., 1928-1929, Reel 59
  - Subways: New York: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Swift & Co., 1930-1932, Reel 59
  - Tender Leaf Tea: See Standard Brands
  - The Widlar Co., 1929, Reel 60
  - Thomas Young Nurseries, Inc., 1928-1930, Reel 220
  - Time Magazine, 1931, Reel 59
  - Toilet goods (See also J.B. Williams Co.), 1922-1928, Reel 59
  - U.S. Food Administration, 1917-1918, Reel 198
  - U.S. Industrial Alcohol, 1924-1930, Reel 198
  - U.S. Marine Corps: See New business
  - U.S. Rubber Co., 1916-1925, Reel 198
  - Underwear: See William Carter Co.
  - Union Tobacco Co.: Herbert Tareyton Cigarettes, 1928-1929, Reel 198
  - Universal Pictures, 1937-1938, Reel 59
  - Urbana Wine Co., 1934, Reel 59
  - Vanity Fair Silk Mills, 1923, Reel 198
  - Vimms: See Lever Brothers
  - Ward Baking Co., 1940-1943, Reel 444-445
  - Warner Bros.: See Miscellaneous Accounts
  - Welch Grape Juice, 1928, Reel 198
  - William Carter Co. (Underwear)
    - 1923-1930, Reel 37-38
    - 1925-1930, Reel 195
  - William R. Warner & Co., 1923-1936, Reel 198
  - Wm. Wrigley Co., 1932, Reel 60
  - Woolworth's: See New business
  - Yuban Coffee: See Arbuckle Bros.
- 16mm Investigations, 1913-1950 and undated
  - Ballantine and Sons
    - Investigations, 1935-1936 (Reel 37)
  - Emerson drug Company
    - Bromo-Seltzer (see also reels 372, 196)
      - Bar investigation in N.Y. and Chicago, 1935 May
      - Analysis of Bromo seltzer sales and consumer investigation, 1935 Apr.
      - Consumer investigation of demand for Bromo-Seltzer at soda fountains, 1935 Apr.
      - Checking 10 N.Y. City drug stores of display, 1935 June
      - Checking of poster locations in Chicago elevator and N.Y. subway, 1935 June
      - Plan for copy test, 1936 Jan.
      - Drug store investigation of Bromo-Seltzer, 1935 Oct.
      - Information on sales of Bromo-Seltzer etc., 1937 May
      - Consumer investigation of urban market for Bromo-Seltzer, 1937 Apr.
      - Survey comparing large and small cities etc., 1937 June
      - Investigations, 1937 Nov.-Dec.
      - Investigations, 1937 Jan.
    - Alkalithia
      - Investigations, 1938 May-Nov.
    - Bromo-Seltzer
      - Bromo-Seltzer copy test by consumer jury, 1939 Dec.
      - Dealer survey in N.Y. City, 1939 May
      - Analysis of newspaper coverage of Bromo-Seltzer, 1939 Apr.
      - Survey of headache remedies recommended by druggists, 1939 May
      - Nationwide consumer survey, 1939 May
      - Circulation and coverage of first 3 markets group, 1939 Nov.
      - Effect of car cart advertising on sales of Bromo seltzer in 4 test cities, 1939 Nov.
      - Nielsen drug index on sales of seltzer and aspirin products, 1940 May
      - Drug store sales--Drug jobbing areas, 1940 July
  - Burry Biscuit Corporation
    - Investigation among Indiana grocers on Burry's Biscuits, 1936 Nov.
    - Consumer survey in N.Y. City on crackers, 1937 May
    - Sales analysis of leading city markets, 1937 June
    - Test of cookie praline, 1937 Oct.
  - William Carter and Company
    - Office investigation knit--underwear for men, 1924 Apr.
    - Mail investigation--Babies' underwear, 1925 Aug.
    - Dealer investigation men, women's, or children's underwear, 1926 Jan.
    - Department store and dry goods chains for Carter Company, 1929 Jan.
    - Baby underwear investigation by 557 physicians, 1930 Aug. (Reel 38)
    - Pre investigation in department stores of Carter underwear in N.Y. City and Utica, 1930 Nov.
    - Market survey of underwear by Holland's magazine in Texas, Oklahoma and Arkansas, 1923 summer
  - Calsodent Company, Inc.
    - Flavor tests of formulas #961-#962, 1930 June
  - Curtis Flying Service, Inc.
    - Analysis of market for pilots and students, 1929 Dec.
  - Chain store--Economic and Financial Research Bureau
    - Comparative analysis of American Kroger and A&P systems, 1925
    - The future of the chain store, 1925
  - Chatham Manufacturing Company
    - Chatham blankets
      - Special analysis of distribution of Airloom blankets, 1929 Aug.